[ WATER DRIPPING ]
[ BREATHING ]
MAN : No .
[ BREATHING CONTINUES ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMING FADES ]
[ PEOPLE CHATTERING ]
MAN : Hey !
Where 's Howard and the rest of the apprentices ?
We left them at the bottom to find their own way up !
They got to learn sometime .
lf you want to be a troubleshooter , you got to know the mine .
ls it all clear down there ?
Yeah , we won 't need these anymore ,
but l wouldn 't go lighting any matches .
Damn methane .
lt 's going to blow this place to shit one of these days .
We ain 't that lucky .
Whoo , hey , come on , now . Knock it off .
[ MEN LAUGHING ]
Howard !
Hey , Howard !
Hey ! Enjoy your walk up ?
Yeah , real joke . Why didn 't you guys wait ?
Look , Landers , you got to get a lot of exercise if you 're going to grapple with Gretchen .
Oh , yeah ? Well , l got a Valentine for her that she 's never going to forget .
Right to the heart , huh ?
lt 's going to be a hot time on Saturday night !
Yee-haw !
[ WHOOPING ]
Hey , Stavinski , you do anything else with that except throw it over your shoulder and burp it ?
Aw , get lost , Axel .
Oh , bunch of clowns . Things haven 't changed a bit . Same as always .
Bet you wish you never came back .
Especially now since Sarah 's going out with Axel .
No skin off my nose .
l don 't give a damn .
Come on , last one into town gets the brew .
Let 's go .
Okay .
Let 's go , guys ! Whoo-ha !
[ ENGINE STARTS AND HORN HONKING ]
[ TIRES SQUEALING ]
[ AIR HORN HONKS ]
Quitting time ! Casanova is here !
HOLLIS : Yee-haw !
Gretchen , it 's me .
Howard , stay away from me .
Hi , babe .
- How are you ? - l 'm fine .
- Good to see you . - Nice to see you too .
Hi , sweetie .
You big brute , l missed you .
[ PEOPLE CLAMOURING AND KISSING ]
Anything l should know ?
No . Of course not .
Gretchen , l want you to be my date for the dance . Will you ?
Dry up .
Gretchen , you know what would look really good on you ?
- What ? - Me .
Suck it in and zip it up , will you ?
Gretchen , why fight it ?
Oof .
Let the good times roll .
All right !
[ AIR HORN HONKS ]
Hi , fellas .
Mabel , this is the best thing that 's happened to this town in years .
Your decorating committee has done one hell of a job .
Well , after all ,
the first Valentine 's dance in 20 years
has to be something special .
Uh , yeah , well , uh ,
of course , you 're right , Mabel , but l think we 'd all be better off
if you played down the fact
that it 's the first Valentine 's dance in 20 years ,
if you know what l mean .
Let 's just concentrate on having a good time Saturday night
and put all that other business to rest .
My thoughts exactly , Mayor .
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
Hi , guy .
Oh , come on , you clowns !
Help Miss Osborne pick those things up .
[ LAUGHTER ]
What the hell are you kids doing in here ?
You 're supposed to be decorating the room ,
not each other .
MAYOR : Where you going , son ?
Where l always go this time of day - -
for another beer and a real good nose pick .
Ooh ! l 'm sorry , TJ .
l don 't think he likes being back in the mine very much .
MAYOR : Well , that 's too bad .
Nobody told him to go out to the West Coast .
lt 's not my fault he couldn 't make it on his own .
But now that he 's back here ,
he 's my son and he 's working in the mine .
You guys better put those things back where you found them ,
or l 'll turn you both upside down . Especially you .
This is my date , Chief .
Chief , that meeting in Centerville is at 7 : 00 .
Maybe we should hit the road .
Then let 's go . l 'll see you kids later . Bye , Mabel .
- Keep up the good work . - See you , Chief .
l might as well go too .
All of this will have to be rewashed .
l 'm really sorry , Mabel .
[ SCOOFS ]
ANNOUNCER [ ON RADIO ] : This is station QPlD , 940 on your radio dial ...
Oh .
Mayor !
Mayor ?
Mayor , somebody left this for you .
For me ? Who was it ?
l don 't know. lt was already inside when we got here .
Maybe you got a secret admirer , huh ?
[ LAUGHING ]
You in on this , Mabel ?
l 'm afraid not , Mayor .
Oh , no .
No no . Don 't look at me .
l didn 't have a thing to do with it .
[ LAUGHING ]
Oh , well , hell ,
l 've been looking for an excuse
to get off this miserable diet Mrs. Hanniger has me on .
Thanks , Howard .
MAYOR : lf there 's one thing l like better
than Christmas candy , it 's Valentine 's candy .
Have some .
Hey ...
who sent it ?
" From the heart comes a warning
filled with bloody good cheer - -
remember what happened
as the 14th draws near . "
[ GASPS ]
lt can 't be happening again .
[ SIREN WAILING ]
lt 's a bad time ,
this time of year .
Bad things coming .
My words , you hear .
Beware the 14th ...
- ... if you value your life . HOWARD : Here we go again .
How many times is he going to tell this story ?
PATTY : Oh , let him tell it . l love fairy tales .
This ain 't no fairy tale , little girl .
lf you don 't take it seriously ,
you 're a fool .
Ohh !
HOLLIS : Hurt yourself ?
Axel , are you okay ?
Oh , no . Let me see .
l know what l 'm talking about .
l 'm telling you now ,
this town is a-cursed .
Now it started 20 years ago .
lt was the night of the Valentine 's Day dance
at the Union Hall - -
the biggest event of the year .
lt had been a tradition for over 100 years .
Everybody was there , except for seven miners
who were out at the Henniger Mine ,
five of them still down below .
Two supervisors were waiting for the men to come up .
Anxious to get to the party ,
they left before the men were safely out
failing to check the methane gas levels
in the tunnels down below .
[ EXPLOSION ]
The five men were buried alive
as the town continued its party .
[ BOTH LAUGHING ]
For six weeks , we dug around the clock
to try to save them .
After we broke through ,
one man was found alive .
l was the one who found him .
[ SCREAMING ]
Harry Warden spent the next year in the state mental hospital .
Exactly one year later ,
on Valentine 's Day ,
he came back to town .
He killed the two supervisors
who had left their posts the year before .
Then he cut out their hearts
and stuffed them into heart-shaped candy boxes .
That night at the dance we found the boxes ,
blood dripping out the sides .
lnside was a note - -
a warning from Harry
never to hold a Valentine 's dance
ever again .
Every February 14 ,
Harry comes back to town ,
his pickax stained with blood ,
waiting in the shadows of the Henniger Mine ...
just for someone to kill
should they not heed his warning .
lt could be you .
l know what l 'm saying .
You forget about having a party at all on Saturday night ,
or you may not live to see daylight .
[ HOWARD BLOWS RASPBERRY AND LAUGHTER ]
Laugh now ...
but you 'll be sorry you didn 't listen to me .
HOLLIS : Uh-oh .
Come on , Hap , lighten up .
HAPPY : lt 's a stupid legend .
SARAH : lt gives me the creeps .
PATTY : Hi , you guys . Who ordered the Moosehead ?
l did , you gorgeous slab of female fleshiness .
[ JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING AND ALL SINGING ]
l hate that song .
l mean , it 's , like , uh - -
hey , where you going ?
l just want to put on some music , okay ?
Be my guest .
Excuse me .
lt 's your own fault . You know that , don 't you , TJ ?
Never said it wasn 't .
Then why can 't you just accept things the way they are ?
Maybe because l don 't like the way things are .
Excuse me .
[ SIREN WAILING ]
Yes , all right .
Thank you . Thank you very much .
l have to call in the morning .
The administration office is closed at night .
The nurse that 's on duty doesn 't know a thing .
Well , she 's got to know whether he 's there or not .
l just hope this is some kind of joke
and the kids are just trying to scare the hell out of us .
lf it is a joke , l want every one of those kids strung up ,
starting with that damn Howard Landers !
Well , it 's a human heart , all right .
A young woman , about 30 years old .
What the hell are you guys doing with a loose heart ?
Looks like a butcher ripped this thing out .
What 's going on over in Valentine Bluffs ?
You remember Harry Warden ?
God , of course l remember .
Those were terrible murders .
God , l thought they locked him up in Easftield
20 years ago .
They did .
Are you sure he 's still there ?
We 'll find out in the morning . l 'm checking on it .
Well , gentlemen ,
l 'd say you have your answer .
lt looks like Harry Warden 's back in town .
[ CRICKETS CHIRPING ]
[ HARRY WARDEN BREATHING ]
Well , now ,
l wonder who sent this ?
Jake ?
Ohh .
" Roses are red , violets are blue
one is dead ,
... and so are you " ?
[ SCREAMING ]
No !
No ! Get away ! Get away !
Get away !
No ! No !
[ CONTINUES SCREAMING ]
Get away ! No ! No !
[ GROANING ]
No ! No !
BOY : Hey , this is getting really good .
HOWARD : Don 't put your nose in it .
[ HOWARD LAUGHS ]
[ WHIRRING ]
HOLLIS : Hey , this is what l really call junk food .
How much longer , Hollis ? l 'm freezing .
Hey , relax . This thing ain 't no microwave .
Hey , how about revving it up ?
Man , have l got the munchies .
Yeah , me , too . A little protein patrol , hey , boys ?
HOLLIS : Don 't go poking my meat .
lt 's hardly cooked .
Don 't go sticking your nose in the food .
BOY : lt 's his . He can do what he wants with it .
ls that turkey , Hollis ? l asked for roast beef .
Turkey for the turkey .
[ HARMONICA PLAYING ]
TJ : Here .
Come on , shove over .
[ COUGHING ]
Sure is cold tonight .
Yeah .
[ BLOWS HARMONICA ]
[ BLOWING AND PLAYNG ]
Well , l guess we got ourselves a problem , huh ?
Yeah .
Yeah , l guess so .
What are we going to do about it ?
Well , there ain 't nothing to do about it .
Sarah 's going with me now
and that 's all there is to it .
l ain 't going to back off for you , TJ .
Nobody asked you to go away , TJ .
Come on , Axel , don 't give me any of that horseshit .
l mean , you 're beginning to sound like my old man .
Too bad , man .
Look , you left . You left .
You went away , and we didn 't know where you were
or - - or when the hell you were coming back .
l ain 't going to back off for you , TJ .
You stay the hell away from Sarah .
TJ : All right , all right .
You want a fight , then you got it .
Because you and l both know who Sarah wants .
[ MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO ]
[ SIGHS ]
You were kind of hard on him , Teege .
You can 't exactly blame him .
Sure , it 's not his fault . lt 's nobody 's fault .
l don 't know what to do .
You know , l really do like that son of a bitch .
Hey , remember - -
remember how we used to tear this place apart ?
Eh ? Get drunk , race out to the bluffs ?
HOLLIS : That was great .
l guess things change , huh ?
Nothing stays the same .
[ CAR HORN HONKS ]
CHIEF : W-A-R-D-E-N .
Harry Warden . He was committed under court order
approximately 20 years ago .
Well , l 'm afraid l have no records
of a Harry Warden , past or present .
CHIEF : But how can that be ? He was committed there
under court order .
l 'm sorry . l have no records on him .
Look , in 20 years , any number of things could have happened .
Now if this Harry Warden was committed , as you say ,
then he 's simply no longer here .
And if l have no records on him ,
l have to assume that he 's transferred , he 's released ,
or he 's on the slab . One of three , take your pick .
One out of three ?
Now look , Mrs. Raleigh , you 're going to have to do
a little bit better than that .
Now l have to know what happened to this man
and l have to know what happened to him now .
Now have you checked everything ?
Everything ...
except the microfilms over in central file ,
and it will take several days to check that .
Look , l need answers and l need them fast .
l 'll be waiting for your call .
FEMALE ANNOUNCER [ ON PA ] : Dr. Peyton , 3-5-3 .
Jumping J - -
they don 't even know what the hell happened to him .
Well , w-what do we need to know ?
lt 's got to be Harry .
Maybe we ought to cancel the dance .
Just decide which one you really want .
And now for the big moment - -
will it be number one , or will it be number two ?
Patty , will you be serious ?
This is important .
You can 't have them both , you know .
- l don 't want them both . - Oh , no ?
No .
[ GIGGLES ]
Just what l thought .
Oh , l don 't know . TJ won 't talk to me .
He just sulks all day long .
He ends up making me feel guilty ,
when he 's the one who owes me the apology .
And Axel is not behaving any better .
Oh , Patty , l don 't even want to go to the dance on Saturday night .
Oh , but you got to go .
lt 'll be all right . Just stay with Hollis and me .
Besides , you got to see the dress l got - -
cut down to here , slit up to there .
l may not get out alive .
Mabel ?
Mabel , l got to talk to you .
We got a problem concerning the dance .
Mabel !
Mabel , you back here ?
[ SNIFFS ]
[ WASHING MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Okay . Little John ?
l want you and Mike to check the wall .
TJ ,
take care of the sump .
TJ : You get a pump down there , or l ain 't doing it .
AXEL : You do it or you get your ass out of here for good .
HANNIGER : l 'll do it .
l 'll do it .
What 's bugging him today ?
Son of a bitch is after my ass
because of Sarah .
lf he keeps it up , l 'm going to nail him .
l said move it , Hanniger !
Oh , yeah . Come on , man .
[ LIQUID SPILLING ]
Anytime , loser .
MAN : Hey , that 's it ! Break it up , you two !
TJ , you get your ass up top to crew 17 .
Go !
There ain 't going to be no fighting in my section , Palmer !
Understand ?
What an awful smell .
This is like it was 20 years ago .
l can remember those murders just like it was yesterday .
Jake , you got to get help from Granville .
No , not yet .
lf we call in Granville , we 'll have police crawling all over this place
and we 'll have a hell of a panic on our hands .
You just mention that Harry 's back
and this town won 't be worth the powder to blow it to hell .
Uh , just a minute . Just a minute , boys .
Uh ...
l want you to bring the ambulance around back .
Load her up from there .
l don 't want anybody in town seeing this .
You remember - -
Mabel Osborne died of a heart attack
and that 's all .
You breathe one word of this to anybody
and you 'll have to answer to me .
Wait a minute . What 's this ?
Take her away .
" lt happened once ,
it happened twice .
Cancel the dance or it 'll happen thrice . "
Oh , well ,
th-th-that 's it .
The dance is canceled .
Let 's tear every poster , every banner ,
every decoration down and - - and out of sight .
l don 't want to see a single Valentine 's heart anywhere .
As long as this town is decorated to the hilt ,
Harry 's going to keep on killing .
And - - and get that damn Union Hall locked up .
All right . All right , Mayor .
No , l 'm sorry . There 's nothing l can do about it .
Hey , what 's going on ?
The mayor has canceled the dance
and that 's all there is to it .
Well , in the light of Mabel 's death , he had no choice .
There 'll be no parties , either .
We owe her that much respect .
Mabel would 've wanted us to have the dance .
l mean , she worked so hard on it .
Yeah , you can 't cancel it now .
He 's just looking for an excuse to cancel the dance .
That 's the way it is .
They 'll be no dance tomorrow night
and no parties , either . Do you understand me ?
[ WHIRRING ]
AXEL : Hanniger !
You and me have something to settle !
You bet we do .
[ COUGHING ]
HOLLIS : Howard , you got to chew it .
You don 't blow bubbles with it .
l 'll take care of myself .
How 'd you ever get to be so stupid ?
l 'm going to shower .
TJ , will you stop this ? l don 't want to go with you .
Are you listening to me ?
Nope .
[ SEAGULLS CAWING ]
Remember this spot ?
Of course l remember this spot .
Why didn 't you write me , TJ ?
Why didn 't you call ?
l wanted to , believe me ,
but l couldn 't .
l mean , l really fell on my ass out there .
l made so many mistakes .
But l learned something .
Look ...
give me a chance .
lf you still want me to go away , l will .
But l have to tell you that l love you and l want you back .
How was l supposed to know that , Jessie ?
l honestly didn 't think you were ever coming back .
You just left me here .
Sarah , please .
l 'm sorry .
l 'm so damn sorry .
[ MUSIC PLAYING AND CROWD CLAMOURING ]
Have you seen Sarah ?
Ain 't my turn to watch after her .
[ CRICKETS CHIRPING ]
[ RUSTLING ]
[ DOG BARKING ]
[ WHISPERING ] Damn it , Sarah , why do you do this to yourself ?
How am l going to tell Axel ?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Sarah !
Chief Newby .
l 'm sorry l startled you .
lt 's all right .
ls something the matter ?
No , l 'm - -
l 'm just making my nightly patrol .
Right .
Good night , Chief .
Oh , good night , Sarah .
Give me a beer , Hap .
You hear about Mabel Osborne ?
She got it just the way l said .
Heart attack , my ass .
Well , if we aren 't going to have a Valentine 's dance ,
what are we going to do ?
Why don 't we have a Valentine party ?
ALL : Yeah , a party !
Where ? Newby 's got this whole town locked up , bright guy .
How about my father 's mine , huh ?
- TJ , are you crazy ? Come on . PATTY : The mine !
ln the mine ?
That 'd be great .
lt would . What a blast .
HOLLIS : ln the mine ? That 's exactly what it would be .
Oh , it 'd be great !
Come on , Hollis . We 've got everything we need down there .
We got , uh , let 's see , we got a rec room .
We got a pool table . Everything .
Yeah , in the mine ... where people get killed and eaten .
Beware of Harry Warden .
Whooo !
Shut the fuck up .
Beware of what you make fun of , you little asshole .
- Who ? - You .
Forget about having a party at all tomorrow night
or you 'll be sorry .
[ SIGHS ]
Hey , lighten up , Hap .
Piss on Harry Warden and that damn old legend .
We 're gonna have ourselves a party .
Don 't you go telling nobody .
Don 't say l didn 't warn you .
That settles it then .
We 're going to the mine and we 're going to have ourselves a party .
[ ALL CHEERING ]
Assholes .
[ BRAKES SQUEAL ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ ENGINE REVVING ]
Damn kids. l 'll show them .
Piss on Harry Warden , will they ?
Well , l 'll give them a scare they 'll never forget .
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ LAUGHS ]
[ LAUGHING ]
Ah .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ GROANING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ MAN GROANING ]
[ WIND BLOWING ]
[ CROWD CLAMOURING HAPPILY ]
BOY : Hey , it 's party time .
[ BOY WHOOPS ]
[ POP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO ]
Where are the wieners ?
Hey , Hollis , here 's the wieners !
[ PEOPLE CLAMOURING AND WHOOPING ]
[ CAR ARRIVING ]
Hi , Ben . Anything happen ?
No , it 's been quiet all evening .
Good .
[ WOMAN SPEAKING ON PHONE ]
BEN : That came for you though .
Oh , my God .
Go and get me a coffee , will you , Ben ?
Yeah , sure , Chief .
[ MAN SPEAKING ON PHONE ]
[ WOMAN CONTINUES SPEAKING ON PHONE ]
Mabel .
Yooo ! Does anybody want a beer ?
Eat you up . Mmm !
Whoo !
Hollis , check this out .
[ LAUGHING ]
You asshole !
Hey , who busted the lock ?
- l got the keys right here . BOY : Howard did .
CLOWN : Uh-oh . BOY : Howard .
BOY 2 : Harry Warden did it .
And whoever parked the red Volkswagen out front ,
l want it parked out back with the others like l said .
l don 't want Newby snooping around here .
Let me show you .
[ BALL RATTTLING ]
[ ALL LAUGHING ]
- Hey , hold it . - Whoa .
Hey , John , where you going ?
Sylvia 's gonna get it tonight .
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Talk to you in a minute , okay ?
[ GIRL SCREAMING ]
So you 're looking pretty good , baby face .
What 's the occasion ?
l figured it 'll get Newby off my back .
Besides , l want to get out of this town pretty quick .
You know , l think he really likes you .
[ CHUCKLING ]
l 've got the munchies .
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Hot dogs .
[ WHISTLES ]
Here , Spot .
Hey , what 's going on ? Who is that ?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ MUFFLED SCREAMING ]
[ BUBBLING ]
l , uh , l got a feeling about the mine , Ben .
l 'll - - l 'll check back with you , all right ?
Make sure you call me on the radio if anything comes up .
Will do .
[ DOGS GROWLING ]
Now what the hell is that ?
[ GROWLING ]
Go on !
[ BARKING ]
Go on , get the hell out of here .
[ BARKING CONTINUES ]
[ BARKING STOPS ]
" You didn 't stop the party . "
Stop the party ?
What damn party ?
Stavinski , you couldn 't clean that table with a broom .
Hollis , you don 't even know what pool means .
Hey , guys , check this out . Check this out .
Gretchen , this is for you .
[ BOY SNORTS AND PEOPLE EXCLAIM ]
Oh , wow .
First time l try to snort Coke , man , and l almost drown .
BOY : Next time , try harder .
[ LAUGHTER ]
- Axel , please . - Oh , come on .
- Axel , please don 't . - What 's the matter , baby ?
- Axel , please don 't . - Oh , come on !
Will you please stop it ?
Guess you better back off there , Axel .
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
Back the fuck off , man .
We were doing just fine until you decided to come crawling home .
Well , in case you haven 't noticed , things have changed around here .
She don 't want nothing to do with you .
Do you mind ? l have my own mouth , thank you .
Then why don 't you use it ? Tell him .
Tell me what ?
[ BALL RATTLING ]
She wants to come back with me .
Bullshit , man .
Why don 't you both just back off ?
You 're acting like a couple of jerks .
Oh , well , you just love it , don 't you ?
That 's it !
[ GROANS ]
You son of a bitch !
[ GRUNTING ]
GRETCHEN : Hollis , do something .
Hollis !
[ ALL GRUNTING ]
TJ : Let go .
Shit ! Will you guys knock it off ?
TJ , are you out of shape .
Get out of here !
[ SNIFFLES ]
Are you sure you 're okay ?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Look , l 'm sorry . l didn 't mean for that to happen .
TJ , please stop it .
l just don 't care anymore .
Just leave me alone .
Okay , listen. l showed you how to do it
with the right nostril , right ?
Now you take the straw and you put it up the neck ,
the left nostril , right ? And you snort it .
[ SNORTS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
Come on , loosen up . Let 's have fun .
We 're at a Valentine 's party , for God 's sake .
l got a little punchy myself .
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ CRYING ]
How do you get those down ?
- Pull the rope . - Just pull it ?
Yeah yeah . Release the hook and let it go .
[ YELPS AND BOTH LAUGHING ]
You know what we need ?
Yeah , l got one right here .
No , l meant a couple of beers .
Oh. l 'll go get them .
l 'll go with you .
No , you stay here and l 'll be back in a flash .
Okay ?
Okay , but don 't take too long .
MAN : Back in a minute .
Okay . Bye .
MAN : Bye .
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ MUSIC CONTINUES AND PEOPLE LAUGHING ]
Hey , TJ .
Hey , John , how you doing ?
l 'm doing great . ls something the matter ?
The same old shit .
[ BUBBLING ]
Well , Howard really makes me gag .
You 're not kidding .
lf anyone , l kinda like Tommy .
Oh , l agree .
BOTH : Hi , John . JOHN : Hi , girls .
Yuck , what is this ?
Oh , wow . One of those idiots really thinks he 's funny .
lt 's probably Howard .
[ FOOTSTEPS AND CREAKING ]
[ TAP SQUEAKING AND WATER RUNNING ]
John , is that you ?
John ?
John , if you 're trying to scare me , you 're doing a good job .
[ GASPS ]
Oh !
[ WHIMPERING AND SCREAMING ]
No ! No ! No !
Help ! Help !
Oh no !
No !
Oh !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GURGLING ]
[ RATTLING ]
Sorry l took so long , babe .
Sylvia ?
Sylvia !
All right .
Hey , all right . All right .
Sylvia , l know you 're in there .
And l 'm coming in .
Sylvia .
MAN [ IN SPEAKER ] : Come in , Mobile One .
Mobile One , in .
Jake , you just got a call from Easftield .
A woman named Raleigh . She said it was urgent .
All right . Mobile One , coming in .
Hey , how about a little trip down to the mine ?
- The mine ? - Yeah , it 'll be great . Come on .
lt 's supposed to be like a roller coaster , isn 't it ?
lt 's 2,000 feet down .
That 's okay. lt 'll cheer her up anyway . Come on , Hollis .
Come on , Mike , let 's go .
What ? Hey , Hollis , you going down to the mine ?
- Well - - - Yes . Yes .
Come on . Come on , Hollis .
- Chicken . - Chicken ?
Hey , why don 't we go down to the mine ?
All right . One quick ride down and then right back up .
- Hey , what about gear ? - Yeah , get that six-pack .
[ LAUGHING ]
GRETCHEN : lt 's going to be great , baby !
Ow !
Watch your step . Come on .
- This is ridiculous . - This is gonna be great .
[ HOLLIS HOWLING ]
[ HOLLIS LAUGHING ]
Hollis !
Where do you think you 're going ?
We 're just going to go for a quick ride
and come right back up . Believe me .
You can 't take them down there .
You know the rule . No women in the mine .
We 're gonna come right back up again . Believe me .
- Come on . - Watch your step .
Howard , don 't be a pain in the ass .
Pain in the ass ? What pain in the ass ?
Be careful . Be careful .
HOLLIS : Down we go .
Come on , you guys , hop in the cars . l 'll be right back .
- Yeah , we made it . - You just let me know .
Here , Sarah , put this around you .
Michael . Michael !
Here you go . And a blanket .
Hey , Hollis , you got one for me ?
Here 's one for you . l 'll be right back .
Do you believe we 're really doing this ?
lt 's so dark down there .
On second thought , l think l 'm gonna stay right up here .
Oh , no , you don 't . lf l 'm going down there , baby ,
- you 're going with me . - Oh , great .
DOLLIS : Hey , hold on , everybody . Here we go .
Keep your hands inside .
And pass me that beer .
All right .
Come on , pass a couple up this way .
- Where 's the lantern ? - Right here . You just stick with me .
[ ENGINE CHUGGING ]
Whoo-hoo !
Down she goes .
[ ALL WHOOPING ]
Hold on . Get ready to stop .
[ ALL WHOOPING AND LAUGHING ]
Hey , Hollis , pass me a beer . Want one , Mike ?
GRETCHEN : How far down does it go ?
300 miles deep .
- Come on , Sarah . - Here you go .
You 're down here every night ?
Wow .
Oh , little bit of a free ride . There we go .
Stops all by itself .
Yeah , l hope you kids enjoyed yourself , ' cause we 're going right back up .
[ WOMEN GROAN ]
Oh , that was great , Hollis .
- Let 's do it again . - Howard usually walks .
Oh , let 's do it again , Hollis . Come on .
[ GROANS ]
Hey , where does that go ?
Oh , that leads to an abandoned part .
We don 't go down there anymore .
- Oh , take us on a tour , Hollis . - Yeah .
Yeah , let 's show them around .
All right . All right .
Just because we 're here . Come on .
Keep those blankets wrapped around you .
- You 're gonna get chilly . - Okay , honey .
lt 's cold .
All right , boys and girls , this is called a tipple .
So that 's a tipple .
This is also called a tipple .
- Hey , Howard , come on ! - Coming !
- Hey , Howard , come on ! - l 'm coming !
l just heard something . Probably some rats .
Rats ! You never told me there were rats .
This is the old engine room .
Oh , uh-huh .
Boy , what a nice view back here .
Howard .
Hey , Hollis .
We 'll meet you in 10 minutes over at the main shaft .
HOLLIS : All right . No longer . We 're going straight up .
[ CLATTERING ]
lt 's pretty dark .
How do you like my pad , huh ?
lt 's okay .
l can 't believe you work here .
Yep .
[ SCREAMING ]
- He 's in there ! - What is it ?
What 's the matter ?
He 's in there . He 's in there .
What 's going on ? What 's going on ?
[ CROWD GASPS ]
Dead . He - - he - -
- What are you talking about ? - He killed her .
What are you talking about ?
Dave is dead !
No ! No !
No !
TJ , it 's Sylvia . Somebody 's killed her .
lt 's Harry Warden . He 's here !
Everybody get the fuck out !
Go ! Go ! Go !
[ PEOPLE SCREAMING ]
[ COINS CLICKING ]
Come on , come on !
Son of a bitch must have cut the phone lines .
Okay , now listen . l want you to make sure
that everybody gets out of here .
And l want you to get the chief
and tell him to get here and fast .
Now go !
Sarah , she 's in the mine with the others .
What ?
Her , Hollis and Patty .
They took the railcars down there .
They 're in the mine right now . We gotta get them out .
That 's where that crazy guy probably is . Look , he 'll kill them !
l 'm gonna get her out .
Come on . Come on !
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
Go ! Go !
Come on .
lf anything happens to Sarah , it 'll be your fault .
You never should have let them go down there .
Damn it , let 's just worry about getting them out .
l 'll take the abandoned section ,
you take the level above .
We 'll meet in the main shaft by the elevator .
Hope to God we get there before Harry does .
Good luck .
[ ELEVATOR BUZZING ]
Where is he ?
l don 't know .
HOLLIS : Boo !
[ GIRLS GASP AND HOLLIS LAUGHS ]
Gotcha .
Damn you , Hollis . Where the hell were you ?
l thought you were right behind me .
You must have gone down the wrong tunnel .
Oh , sure we did . You did that on purpose .
Me ? Come on .
Okay .
Watch your head .
Watch your step as well .
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
This is the oldest part of the mine .
Oh , God !
These tunnels were built in the early 1800s .
- Really ? - Yeah , it 's all abandoned now .
Ooh .
We haven 't worked down here in years . Not since ...
Harry Warden .
[ HOWARD YELLS AND ALL SCREAM ]
[ LAUGHING ]
Howard , what do you think you 're trying to do , you jerk ?
Easy , l 've got a hangover .
[ LAUGHING ]
Boy , did you guys jump !
- Howard ! - Ha-ha-ha !
Oh , Howard , you goof .
- Get down out of there . - l 'll go the other way .
- For Pete 's sake . - l know what l 'm doing .
[ PATTY LAUGHING ]
Oh , God , you guys .
Come on . Hold it .
Oh , that feels so good .
[ LAUGHING ]
- Okay . - Okay .
- Get your light . - All right . Okay .
- Okay ? - Yeah .
- You all right ? - Come on .
Get down !
Now stick with us and quit clowning around .
Come on ! l was just having a little bit of fun .
Yeah yeah , sure .
Hey , you guys , where 's Mike and Harriet ?
Maybe Harry Warden got them .
Stop it .
Howard , come along and behave yourself .
Yeah , let 's go .
[ HARRY BREATHING HEAVILY ]
My blanket !
Oh , come on , you 'd forget your head
if it wasn 't tied on with rope . Let 's go .
Come on , it 's freezing down here .
Hey , who 's leading this tour ?
Well , go ahead if you want .
l feel so good .
So do l .
Where are we going now , Hollis ?
Oh , this leads to the main shaft . We 're going up .
How come the walls are so white around here , Hollis ?
l told you . lt 's lime powder .
They put it here to contain explosions
and they put it on the wood so it doesn 't get dry and crack .
Hey , you guys ,
how come Mike and Harriet haven 't come back yet ?
Uh-oh .
[ LIGHT BULBS SHATTERING ]
What 's that ?
l thought l heard something .
Look , it 's probably only rats .
That ain 't no rat .
Come on , let 's go find Mike and Harriet
and get out of here .
- Come on ! - Coming .
[ ENGINE REVVING ]
[ ENGINE STOPS ]
Tommy Whitcomb , what the hell 's the matter with you , anyway ?
Where 's your brains ? How many times have l told you - -
Chief , listen to me . You have to go to the mine .
We were having a party and Harry Warden started killing everybody !
Harry Warden ?
Harry Warden is at the mine .
There 's a bunch of kids trapped down below .
Axel and TJ are trying to get them out .
He killed Sylvia and Dave !
All right . Get back in that car and get home and stay put .
Go on !
[ SIREN BLARING ]
- Mobile One in . BEN : Go ahead , Chief .
Yeah , Ben , call the mayor right away ,
then round up every available man .
Meet me back at the mine .
l think there 's some kids trapped down below .
Out .
Howard , would you get up in front ?
l 'm trying to get up in front !
- Ow ! - l can 't even see .
- Watch your head . - Just stay beside me .
- Okay . - Michael !
Mike !
Why don 't they answer us ?
- Stavinski ! - Mike !
We never should have left them in the first place .
Maybe they 're down there .
- Jesus ! - TJ .
What the hell are you trying to do ?
- Are you all right ? - Yes .
Yeah , we 're fine . What 's the matter with you ?
We gotta get the hell out of here .
Harry Warden is back .
He 's killed Sylvia and Dave up top .
Are you kidding ?
Harry 's dead . Harry died a long time ago .
Will you shut up and listen to me , goddamn it !
Now they 're dead and he 's down here somewhere .
lf you wanna get out of here alive ,
you do exactly as l tell you .
What are we gonna do ?
This better not be your idea of a joke , TJ .
Do l look like l 'm joking ?
Come on . Let 's go .
Wait a minute . Now what about Mike and Harriet ?
Last time l saw them , they were in the engine room .
You check the main shaft .
l 'll take tunnel six and meet you there .
Howard , you stay with the girls and wait for Axel .
- Me ? - Stay with Howard .
- No , Hollis , please ! - Stay back !
Hollis ! Wait a minute !
Howard , you watch the girls !
l don 't even know my way around .
Oh , shit .
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
Michael ?
Harriet ?
Michael and Harriet , this isn 't anytime to be doing anything .
[ GASPS ]
[ CLICK ]
[ GUN COCKS ]
[ CLATTERS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ MOANING ]
[ CLATTERING ]
Oh ! Oh , Jesus !
[ PATTY SCREAMING ]
No .
Oh , God , Hollis !
[ WHIMPERING ]
Oh , Hollis !
Oh , God , Hollis .
Oh .
Oh , it 's not - -
Oh , please , God .
[ PATTY CRYING ]
Come on . He 's dead .
He 's dead ! Come on !
- Come on ! - Patty , come on .
Come on , he 's dead . Now come on .
- Patty ! - No .
Howard , you bastard !
He 's dead . Now come on .
You can 't leave us like this !
Patty , please . Help me .
No !
Leave him alone .
- Let go of me . - No .
Patty , we need the light , damn it !
Okay , come on , Patty . Don 't do this to me .
We have to get out of here .
No !
Stop it !
[ SLAP ]
[ CRYING ]
Okay okay , come on .
[ GASPS ]
Oh , my God .
Where are the others ?
We saw him . He was standing right there .
Harry Warden 's down here .
Come on , let 's go .
- Come on . PATTY : No !
Let 's go ! Come on !
Where the hell is TJ ?
He went looking for Mike and Harriet .
He told us to stay here .
[ PATTY SOBBING ]
Now come on . The cage is right up ahead .
Let 's go !
Keep moving . You 're gonna be fine .
- Axel , please ! No ! - Hold on .
Oh , let go of me .
l don 't want to leave him there .
- Shh . Shh . - Let 's go back and get him .
l don 't want to - -
oh , please , Axel , no .
Patty , stop it !
l don 't want to leave him there .
You 'll be fine . You 're gonna be just fine .
Oh , God , where are you taking us ?
Keep moving . We 're almost there . We 're almost there .
Keep moving . You 're doing fine . You 're doing fine .
That 's it .
God , where are we going ?
l can 't make it anymore .
Shut up . Yes , you can .
Come on . Let 's go .
- l can 't ! - Let 's go .
[ FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ]
Shit .
[ AXEL YELLS AND TJ GROANS ]
lt 's TJ .
Aw , shit !
What the fuck do you think you 're doing ?
l 'm sorry , man . l thought you were Harry .
Do l look like Harry ? Where 's Howard ?
- He ran off . - Oh , that jerk !
He 's never gonna find his way out of here alone .
Hollis is dead .
Look , we gotta get Sarah and Patty up top ,
get some help and come back for the others .
- Come on . - Okay , let 's go .
Come on . Come on . Let 's get going .
PATTY : Okay .
[ SIREN BLARING ]
[ SIREN STOPS ]
MAN [ ON RADIO ] : Mobile One , come in .
Mobile One .
Come in , Mobile One .
Watch your step .
Okay . l can 't even see .
We 're almost there .
Shh ! Keep your voices down .
- Come on . - Shh !
Please , hurry .
Shh ! Keep your voices down .
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
He smashed the control panel .
There 's no way we 're getting out of here .
What ?
What are we gonna do ?
Climb .
- Come on . - No .
Come on .
TJ : Watch your footing now .
PATTY : Axel , please slow down .
GRETCHEN : Patty , you 're okay . l 'm right behind you .
Keep going .
[ WHIMPERING ]
TJ : Come on . Come on . Don 't look down .
Keep looking up .
GRETCHEN : Patty , just do as he says , and you 'll be fine .
l promise .
l don 't want to go any further .
Please , can we stop and go another way ?
SARAH : There 's no other way . Now move it , damn it !
Axel , you 'll have to go slower .
l 'm right behind her . She keeps stopping .
Go slower , okay ?
Oh !
l 'm scared of heights , you guys .
l 'm not going any further .
l 'm stopping right here .
Sarah , Sarah . Give her a hand .
Now l 'm behind you .
l 'm right behind you . Come on .
Okay . Okay . Stay close .
Okay , l 'm right behind you .
Attagirl . Keep moving .
Good girl .
[ PATTY SCREAMING ]
[ THUDS ]
Come down . Come down , quick . Down .
Don 't look .
Don 't look at him . Come on .
Patty , over here .
Now he 's up top .
That bastard 's really playing games with us .
We can beat him if we can get to the rail cars .
Then , come on . l know a shortcut through the sump .
lt 's over there .
Watch your step .
Come on .
Come on . Come on . Nice and slow .
Let 's go . Let 's go . Slowly .
TJ , take the girls over
and give me a yell when you 're across .
Okay .
Go .
Watch your head .
Watch your step .
Okay .
Okay , Axel , we 're clear . Come on over .
[ AXEL COUGHS ]
[ WATER SPLASHING ]
Axel ?
Axel !
TJ , do something .
There 's nothing l can do .
lt 's 60-feet deep .
Gosh !
We 've got to get out of here .
We can 't just leave him here .
Move it !
lt 's too late for Axel .
Come on .
Okay , you just hug along the left side of the wall .
Now just keep going . Go on . Continue .
- But why - - - Just do as he says .
[ WOOD CREAKING ]
TJ ?
Answer us !
TJ !
[ GASPS ]
- He 's - - - Shh !
Let 's go this way .
Come on . Go .
Careful .
[ WOOD CREAKING ]
Shh !
Okay , there 's gotta be some way out of here .
- Yeah . - Come on , keep going .
This way .
Come on .
[ GROANING ]
[ ROCKS RUSTLING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SIRENS BLASTING ]
- They 're down there ? - Yeah .
[ SOBBING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Sarah ! Sarah !
Oh , TJ .
Thank God .
Shh !
[ CRYING ]
Come on .
TJ ?
lt 's okay . l just got hit .
Come on . We 've got to hurry .
The elevator isn 't working .
We 're gonna have to go in this way . Let 's go .
[ PEOPLE CLAMURING ]
Jump .
[ PEOPLE CLAMOURING ]
TJ !
SHERRIF : All right , watch this thing coming .
Oh my God .
Sarah , move it !
Get in . Get in !
Watch out !
[ GRUNTING ]
Axel .
Why ?
[ RUMBLING ]
Go .
Come on .
He 's in there .
Are you two all right ?
lt isn 't Harry Warden .
Yeah. l know , TJ .
l got a call from Easftield late this evening .
They said that Harry Warden died five years ago .
But then who is it ?
lt 's Axel .
Oh my God .
Okay . Well , you ...
My God , it was on Valentine 's Day
that Harry Warden killed Axel 's father .
- Let 's get in there . - Yeah .
AXEL : Come on . Let 's get it off . Get it off .
He 's alive !
- My God . TJ : Sarah !
Oh , my God ! Oh !
TJ : Sarah !
TJ , l have to see him .
Axel .
Why ?
[ GASPS ]
Help me , please .
Hanniger , l 'll be waiting in hell for you !
Harry ? Harry , l 'm coming .
This whole fucking town is going to die !
We 're coming back , you bastards !
[ LAUGHING ]
Sarah , be my bloody Valentine .
[ LAUGHS ]
[ HUMMING ]
[ LAUGHING MANICALLY ]